schluter.com 2012-05-22

# Schluter-Systems offers a number of services that do not require a customer’s or user’s personal information. However, some of our services do require such information. In an ongoing effort to improve all of our services, we may gather personal information from you when you visit our site. This includes the collection of non-personally identifiable information. Through the use of computer "cookies" we collect data such as your IP address, browser type, domain name, and specific Schluter web pages through which you have clicked. This data is collected automatically and utilized to help us improve our website. Additional information regarding computer cookies and how to disable them is described below. Here are the types of information we may collect:

PRIVACY POLICY
This policy applies to the operation of our website (www.schluter.com) and all associated services
provided by Schluter Systems L.P and any of its affiliated companies. Our company and its
affiliates are committed to respecting and maintaining the privacy of all personal information,
which is gathered when you access our website or use our services.
When and what personal information do we collect?
Schluter-Systems offers a number of services that do not require a customer’s or user’s personal
information. However, some of our services do require such information. In an ongoing effort to
improve all of our services, we may gather personal information from you when you visit our site.
This includes the collection of non-personally identifiable information. Through the use of
computer "cookies" we collect data such as your IP address, browser type, domain name, and
specific Schluter web pages through which you have clicked. This data is collected automatically
and utilized to help us improve our website. Additional information regarding computer cookies
and how to disable them is described below.
Here are the types of information we may collect:
Information you provide – Schluter-Systems does require that personal information be given
when requesting information, samples, or product. Should you apply to open an account with us,
we will ask you for your name, billing address, shipping information, e-mail address, and
telephone number. If you qualify for an account, additional information may be required. In some
instances, we may ask you to provide us with optional information to better serve you. This
account data will not be shared with any third party without your consent (though we will
cooperate fully should circumstances arise where we are required by law).
User communications –When you send e-mail or other communications to Schluter-Systems, we
reserve the right to save these communications to process your request, respond to your
inquiries, and/or improve our customer services.
Links – Schluter-Systems may provide links that allow us to track the path of said links as
followed by the customer or user. We use this information to improve our website, e-newsletters,
services, etc.

Schluter-Systems will not share your personal information with other companies or
individuals outside of Schluter-Systems except in the following instances:
        with trusted service providers that require access to your information in order to perform
         operational or other support services;
        with a third party(s) to whom such disclosure has been authorized through your consent;
        where disclosure is required by law.
Why do we collect your personal information?
Schluter-Systems collects your personal information to provide you with the best services
possible. We do not rent or sell customer information to outside marketers.
Where is your personal information kept?
Your personal information is kept at secure locations and on secure servers owned and operated
by Schluter-Systems, located at either our offices, our subsidiary offices, or at the offices of our
providers. We review your information internally. No third parties are involved. After we review
your information, we either discard it or store it in our files. We do not sell personal information or
provide it to third parties.
Use of Cookies:
Cookies and other tracking technologies can serve to recall personal information previously
indicated by a web user. A “cookie” is a small text file that may be used, for example, to collect
information about web site activity. Cookies are identifiers that are transferred to your computer‘s
hard drive through our web browser to enable our system to recognize your browser. Employing
cookies enables our web server to recognize you have returned to a specific page. Most
browsers are initially set up to accept cookies. If you wish, you can reset your browser to refuse
all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. However, if a user refuses a cookie,
he/she may not be able to use some of the features available on the website.
Children Online Privacy Protection Act:

Our site and services are directed to adults; they are not directed to children under the age of 13.
We operate our site in compliance with the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act and will not
knowingly collect or use personal information from anyone under the age of 13.
How can you gain access to you personal information?
Upon written request only, Schluter-Systems will provide you with the existence, use, and
disclosure of, as well as access to, your personal information. This request can be sent to the
address provided below.
How do we protect your personal information?
When your personal information is held within Schluter Systems L.P. or on its behalf, we
will take all reasonable steps to protect the information from unauthorized access or
disclosure.
Changes to the privacy policy
Please know that Schluter-Systems reserves the right to change this privacy policy from time to
time. If we change our policy and such changes alter the use of your personal identifiable
information in a manner different from that provided herein, then we will post changes on our
website and revise the effective date of the privacy policy textual link, which appears at the
bottom of the page. Your continued use of the website and/or use of our services after changes
to our privacy policy shall constitute your acceptance of such changes. We encourage users
and visitors to frequently check this page for any changes to this policy.
Further Information: If you have any questions about the privacy policy, please send them to:
Privacy Policy
c/o Schluter-Systems
194 Pleasant Ridge Road
Plattsburgh, NY 12901
Effective date; May 2008.
